Guide to the U.S. Agency for International Development Records, Programs, and Itineraries 1960-1968
U.S. Agency for International Development Records, Programs, and Itineraries
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
U.S. Agency for International Development Records, Programs, and Itineraries, 1960-1968
5384
U.S. Agency for International Development
6 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
This collection consists of the program and itinerary for each of the various AID sponsored training programs carried out in the U.S. and other countries.
6 cubic feet
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
U. S. Agency for International Development
On September 4, 1961 the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 vas signed into law. On November 4, 1961 the Agency for International Development was set up in the Department of State to succeed the International Cooperation Administration. The main objective of AID was to combine the various foreign assistance programs into one program which would assist the underdeveloped countries in maintaining their independence by making them self-supporting nations. The Development Loan Fund, created in 1957 was incorporated in AID and AID was made responsible for foreign economic assistance and the coordination of military assistance.
The administration of the foreign aid program was largely reorganized at the time of the establishment of AID. The responsibility for operations was shifted from functional offices to geographic offices. Four regional offices representing Latin America, Europe and Africa, the Near East and South Asia, and the Far East were established with each having an assistant administrator responsible to the Administrator of AID. The effect of reorganization has been to plan aid on a country by country basis rather than project by project as was formerly done.
The working concepts that are the basis for the operations of AID are:
1. Long-term development assistance based on well-conceived program plans prepared by the developing countries in cooperation with the United States will result in significant progress toward self-sustaining growth during the 1960's.
2. Assistance will be successful in relation to the ability and willingness of developing countries to help themselves.
3. Aid programs will be tailored to the capacity of a country to use assistance effectively, as well as to the varied needs of different countries with respect to the threat of Communism. The nature of the aid to be used will depend on the situation in the particular country.
4. In order to encourage self-help, loans on reasonable terms are preferable to grants for long-term development and repayment should be in dollars rather than local currency.
5. Assistance to the less-developed countries is the collective responsibility of the developed countries and a greater share of the responsibility for aid should be borne by our allies.
U. S. Agency for International Development
The function of the International Training Division is to prepare cooperating country nationals to perform important roles in their nations' development programs. The participant training program's objectives are to improve the technical, professional, and managerial skills and knowledge of participants, and to introduce attitudes and values essential to social and economic development. AID is responsible for training approximately 6,500 persons annually in the U.S., plus 2,200 abroad. Each training program is designed by AID's International Training Division to meet the needs of a specific country or project within that country.
The Division regularly makes use of numerous other government agencies in carrying out its training functions. These agencies make available their technical knowledge and facilities to the appropriate training programs.
This collection consists of the program and itinerary for each of the various AID sponsored training programs carried out in the U.S. and other countries. The training programs are arranged under the Bureaus which sponsored them and include such diverse fields as agriculture, labor, industry and mining, transportation, public health, housing, public administration, community development, public safety and many others.
SUBJECTS
Names:
United States. Agency for International Development
Subjects:
Economic development.; Economic assistance, American.; Economic assistance - International cooperation
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
CONTAINER LIST
- Information About Agency for International Development, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Contains 13 booklets on the Agency for International Development
- Information About the Agency for International Development, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Contains 12 booklets on international aid
- Program and Itinerary, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Latin-American Trade Union, International Cooperation Administration
- Los Companeros, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Partners of the Alliance News, March 1966
- "A Hand, not a Handout", 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  US Agency for International Development, July 12 1965
- Agency for International Development, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Press Releases: February 1 through February 7 1966
- Agency for International Development, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Press Releases: March 15 through March 21 1966
- US Agency for International Development, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Partners of the Alliance: The Grassroots Approach, 2 booklets
- US Agency for International Development, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Partners of the Alliance: Basic Proceedings, First Inter-American Conference; June 10-11 1965
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Indonesia; General Participant Training; "Price Statistics"
- Viet-Nam Industrial Relations Development Team, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  August 21 1967 - October 21 1967
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Chinese: Business Accounting Observation Team
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Thailand Community Development: High Level Administration, Training and Field Operation
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Thailand: Training in Labor and Price Statistics
- Vietnam, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Period of visit: June 22 - October 15 1967
- Thailand, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Chidchand Hansasuta, period of visit October 12 1967 - April 20 1968
- Drs. Panitchpakdi Prom and Buasri Thamrong, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Manpower and Educational Development Planning, Thailand; August 14 - September 30 1966
- Mr. Nguyen Quang Quynh, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Professor and Head of the Research and Documentation Division National Institute Administration Saigon, Vietnam; June 16 - August 10 1966
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 19)
  India: Employment Services Training
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Part II Pakistan: Development of Statistical Services (Training in Price Statistics)
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 21)
  India: Workers Education Training
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 22)
  Philippines: Financial Management Impact Team
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 23)
  Labor Ministry Training: Labor Administration
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 24)
  Asian Productivity Organization: Food Industry Study Team: Republic of China, India, Japan, Republic of Korea, Nepal, Pakistan, the Philippines, Thailand
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 25)
  Industrial Development and Management Studies: The Formation and Flow of Capital: China, Honduras, Nicaragua, Peru, Philippines, Trinidad, Turkey
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 26)
  Republic of China: Paints and Resins Productivity Study Team
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 27)
  China: Industrial Investment Promotion Productivity Council
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 28)
  China: Public Administration and Manpower Improvement
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 29)
  China: Pulp and Paper Productivity Study Team
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 30)
  China: Labor Administration Productivity Team
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 31)
  Republic of China: Labor's Role in Productivity
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 32)
  Korea: Metals Industry Study Team
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 33)
  Korean Manpower Team
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 34)
  Korea: Industrial development Study Team
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 35)
  Philippines: Industrial Chemistry Team
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 36)
  Philippines: Industrial Real Estate Team
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 37)
  Philippines: Shoe Manufacturing Team
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 38)
  Philippines: Pharmaceutical Productivity Team
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 39)
  Republic of the Philippines: Development Bankers' Productivity Team
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 40)
  Philippines: Public Administration Improvement
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 41)
  Philippines: Manpower Development and Utilization
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 42)
  Indonesia: Industrial Relations Training
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 43)
  Indonesia: Labor Inspection and Statistics
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 44)
  Indonesia: Social Security Training Program
- Program and Itinerary: Indonesia (Box 1, Folder 45)
  Labor Leadership Training, Employment Service, Department of Labor Employment Service, Labor Safety Inspection Training, Labor leadership Training, Labor Leadership Training, Employment Security, Labor Leadership Training, Executive Leadership Study Team,
- Program and Itinerary: Vietnam (Box 1, Folder 46)
  Labor Institutions, Labor Relations Team, 2nd Industry Productivity Study Team, Industrial Productivity Study Team, Labor Institutions,
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 47)
  Pakistan: Development of Statistical Services
- Mr. Nguyen van Tung, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  Chief, Vocational Training Service, Control Directorate of Manpower Ministry of Labor, Saigon, Vietnam
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 49)
  Iran: Labor and Price Statistics
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 50)
  Iran: Social Security Training Program
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 51)
  Multi-Country Industry Orientation Study Team
- Program and Itinerary: Cyprus (Box 1, Folder 52)
  Trade Union Team, Labor Training Division
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 53)
  Productivity and Employment Study: Greece, Peru, Philippines
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 54)
  Greece: Management Association Study
- Program and Itinerary: India (Box 1, Folder 55)
  Trade Union Development and Worker's Education Training, Employment Market Information, Tools Jigs and Fixtures Productivity Team, Instruments Industry Productivity Team, Labor and Price Statistics, Collection of Employment Market Information Project, Rol
- Program and Itinerary: India (Box 1, Folder 56)
  Various International and Domestic Programs and Itineraries
- Agency for International Development, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  Press releases, itineraries, programs and staff papers regarding the Near East
- Staff Papers Summarized Work done in Third World, 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 59)
  India: Employment Services Team
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 60)
  Trade Union Development, Worker's Education Training
- Program and Itinerary (Box 1, Folder 61)
  Vietnam: Farmers Trade Union Team
- Programs and Itineraries (Box 1, Folder 62)
  For Labor and Industrial works in the Near and Far East, specifically India, Pakistan, China, and Cyprus
- Program and Itinerary: Peru (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Booklets concerning Industry
- Program and Itinerary: Ecuador (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Labor Training Group and Highway Equipment Maintenance Study Team Booklets
- Program and Itinerary: Costa Rica (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Area Development, Small Store Retailing, Insurance Agents, Furniture Industry booklets
- Program and Itinerary: Venezuela (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Metal Working Industries, Labor Employment Services, and Social Security Training Booklets
- Program and Itinerary: Trinidad and Tobago (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Labor-Management-Government relations
- Program and Itinerary: Mexico (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Labor Union Metal Workers, Graphic Arts Union Cooperative Housing
- Program and Itinerary: Chile (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Booklets regarding trade, industry and social security
- Program and Itinerary: British Guiana (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Booklets regarding Labor and Trade Unions
- Program and Itinerary: Brazil (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Labor, Industry, Trade and Labor Union booklets
- Program and Itinerary: Brazil (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Booklets concerning labor and trade unions, and infrastructure study teams
- Program and Itinerary: Brazil (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Booklets concerning paper and cardboard workers, food labor, electrical engineering and chemical and oil refineries
- Program and Itinerary: Bolivia (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Booklets regarding telecommunications, petroleum, textile workers, white collar unions, Chauffers, teachers, and private bank employee unions
- Program and Itinerary: Vietnam (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Labor and Price Statistics
- Program and Itinerary: Liberia (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Program and Itinerary: Libya (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Program and Itinerary: Honduras (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Labor Training and Education in Labor Statistics
- Program and Itinerary: Antigua, West Indies (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Labor Training Union Organization and Administration
- Program and Itinerary: St. Lucia, West Indies (Box 2, Folder 18)
  Labor Training: Labor Administration and Industrial Relations
- Program and Itinerary: El Salvador (Box 2, Folder 19)
  Latin American Trade Union Training, Group A
- Program and Itinerary: El Salvador (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Latin American Trade Union Training, Group B
- Program and Itinerary: Dominican Republic (Box 2, Folder 21)
  Industrial Safety and Hygiene
- Program and Itinerary: Dominican Republic (Box 2, Folder 22)
  Labor Training, Latin American group XXV
- Program and Itinerary: Colombia (Box 2, Folder 23)
  Resources development Study Team
- Program and Itinerary: Industrial Development and Management Studies (Box 2, Folder 24)
  Bolivia, Peru, Trinidad; Bolivia, Ecuador, El Salvador; Bolivia, Honduras, India, Nepal, Philippines, Trinidad; Bolivia, Costa Rica, Greece, Peru, The Philippines, republic of China, Turkey; Bolivia, El Salvador, Trinidad; Peru, Philippines, Trinidad; Per
- Turkey Worker's Education team, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Agency for International Development; July 15 - September 1 1965
- Turkey Collective Bargaining Team, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  July 30 - October 21 1965
- Program and Itinerary: India (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Engineering Study Team, Industrial Hygiene and Safety
- Program and Itinerary: Jordan (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Industrial Management Study
- Program and Itinerary: Panama (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Training in Manpower Statistics
- Program and Itinerary: Paraguay (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Industrial Development Team
- Program and Itinerary: Philippines (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Small and Medium Size Industry Study
- Program and Itinerary: Pakistan (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Labor Relations Training, Labor Management relations, Foundry Industry Productivity Study Team, Development of Statistical Services, Tools, Jigs and Fixtures Productivity Study Team
- Program and Itinerary: Turkey (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Forest L. Miller mission to Turkey; Industrial Relations Training; Training in Labor and Price Statistics; Mediation and Voluntary Arbitration Team; Statistical Research; Industrial Relations Training Hasan Turkey; Industrial Relations Training Enver Turg
- Program and Itinerary: Turkey (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Employment Service, Ministry of Labor; Trade Union Organizing Methods and Techniques Team; Training in Labor and Price Statistics; Structure, Function and Administration of National Trade Unions Teams; Labor Relations Services Mediation and Arbitration Te
- Program and Itinerary: Turkey (Box 3, Folder 11)
  Worker Education Team; Trade Union Collective Bargaining Team; Labor and Price Statistics; Collective Bargaining and Duties and Functions of Trade Union Officers; Organizing and Establishing Local Unions; Union Finance and Administration; Organizing, Meth
- Program and Itinerary: Turkey (Box 3, Folder 12)
  Structure, Function and Administration of National Unions (Internal Organizations); Industrial Health and Safety Team; Contract Negotiations and Research Teams; Trade Union Cooperative Team; Labor and Price Statistics; Turkey Industrial relations Training
- Program and Itinerary: Turkey (Box 3, Folder 13)
  Industrial Relations Training; Industrial Relations Training; Fruit and Vegetable Processing and Canning Study team; Light Metal Fabrication Study Team; Marketing and Sales Study; Industrial and Production Engineering Team; Industrial Relations Training
- Program and Itinerary: Turkey (Box 3, Folder 14)
  Executive Administration Training; Manpower Planning and Programming; Women's Role in Trade Union Movement; Worker's Education; Industrial Relations in the Food Processing and Agriculturally Allied Industries; Trade Union Journalism and Communication; Man
- Program and Itinerary: Bolivia (Box 3, Folder 15)
  Bank Employees Trade Union team; Trade Union Communication Workers Team; Labor training, Factory Workers, Labor Relations and Productivity; Miner's Union; Airline Workers; Observations in US Labor Organizations; Teachers Basic Trade Union Program; Mine Wo
- Program and Itinerary (Box 3, Folder 16)
  Bolivia, Honduras and Venezuela
- Morris B. Wallach Mission to Brazil, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  October 17 to November 18 1966
- Venezuela, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  August 17 - September 17 1966
- Kenneth G. van Auken Mission to Morocco, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  October 21 to December 17 1966
- Multi-Country Specialized Labor Union Technical Training Team, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  February 19 - March 4 1966
- Peru Railroad Workers Trade Union Team, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  August 12 0 October 3 1967
- Time Study Practice and Procedure, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Training Manual No. 111
- Fire Control Training, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  Training Manual No. 115
- Economic Development Case Problems, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Department of State, Agency for International Development; Training Manual No. 144
- Economics of Industrial Development, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Department of State, Agency for International Development; Training Manual No. 143
- The Art of Making Molds, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Department of State, Agency for International Development; Training Manual No. 142
- Basic Course in Production Planning and Control, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Department of State, Agency for International Development; Training Manual No. 141
- A Suggestion System, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Department of State, Agency for International Development; Training Manual No. 112
- Conference Leadership: Manual of Instruction, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Department of State, Agency for International Development
- Work Simplification for Increased Productivity, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Department of State, Agency for International Development; Training Manual No. 107
- Line-Staff Relationships, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  Department of State, Agency for International Development; Training Manual No. 134
- Performance Discussions, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  Department of State, Agency for International Development; Training Manual No. 135
- Purchasing (Supervisory Trainee Program) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Department of State, Agency for International Development; Training Manual No. 81
- Production Planning and Control, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Department of State, Agency for International Development; Training Manual No. 82
- Manufacturing and Manufacturing Engineer, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Department of State, Agency for International Development; Training Manual No. 83
- Job Analysis, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Department of State, Agency for International Development; Training Manual No. 84
- Plant Maintenance and Housekeeping, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Department of State, Agency for International Development; Training Manual No. 85
- Paperwork Simplification, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  International Cooperation Administration; Training Manual No. 86
- Job Evaluation Operating Procedures, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  International Cooperation Administration; Training Manual No. 87
- The Art of Motivating People, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  International Cooperation Administration; Training Manual No.88
- Production Scheduling and Control, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  International Cooperation Administration; Training Manual No.89
- Time and Motion Study, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  International Cooperation Administration; Training Manual No.90
- Management Primer: Management and Productivity, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  International Cooperation Administration; Training Manual No.91
- Management Primer: Enterprise Organization, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  International Cooperation Administration; Training Manual No.92
- Management Primer: Human Relations in Management, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  International Cooperation Administration; Training Manual No.93
- Management Primer: Personnel Administration, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  International Cooperation Administration; Training Manual No.94
- Management Primer: Control and Supervision, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  International Cooperation Administration; Training Manual No.95
- Management Primer: Records and Reports, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  International Cooperation Administration; Training Manual No.96
- Management Primer: Financial Management, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  International Cooperation Administration; Training Manual No.99
- Management Primer: Distribution and Sales, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  International Cooperation Administration; Training Manual No.100
- Management Primer: Research and Public Relations, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  International Cooperation Administration; Training Manual No.101
- Management Primer: Management Glossary, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  International Cooperation Administration; Training Manual No.102
- Sales Promotion Methods, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  International Cooperation Administration; Training Manual No.103
- Distribution Methods, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  International Cooperation Administration; Training Manual No.104
- Wholesale Merchandising, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  International Cooperation Administration; Training Manual No.105
- A Basic Course in Work Study, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  International Cooperation Administration; Training Manual No.106
- Foreman Training Course (Box 5, Folder 25)
  International Cooperation Administration; Training Manual No.108
- Sales Training and Distribution, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  International Cooperation Administration; Training Manual No.109
- Executive's Role in an Organization, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  International Cooperation Administration; Training Manual No.110
- A Suggestion System, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  International Cooperation Administration; Training Manual No.112
- Science of Human Relations, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  International Cooperation Administration; Training Manual No.113
- Taking Annual Inventory, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  International Cooperation Administration; Training Manual No.114
- Basic Course in Work Sampling, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  International Cooperation Administration; Training Manual No.116
- Marketing Research, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  International Cooperation Administration; Training Manual No.117
- Wood Furniture Industry, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  International Cooperation Administration; Training Manual No.118